<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Professional developer</title><link>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Professional developer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Junit 5 Parallel Test Execution With Maven</title><link>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/java_multithread_junit5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/java_multithread_junit5/</guid><description>
Introduction We need fast-build pipelines. This is because we need fast feedback from our pipeline in order to be more productive. If something is wrong with our code, then we want our pipeline to fail fast. To accomplish that, you may decide to allow parallel test execution for tests in your project. This post describes how to do that with Maven and Junit 5.
Getting Started With Junit 5 and Maven To get started with Junit 5, you need to import the following dependency into the project:</description></item><item><title>Why Should You, as a Software Developer, Learn Soft Skills?</title><link>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/soft_skills/soft_skills/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/soft_skills/soft_skills/</guid><description>
Here are several reasons: We work in teams.
The better we know how to communicate with people in a team, the better we will be. Remember, your whole company is one big team. We use programming languages to communicate between each other.
Hardware doesn't need a programming language to process our intentions. All languages compile at the end in machine code. Programming languages are here to help us communicate ideas. The cleaner(more readable) code you write, the more understandable it will be to other developers.</description></item><item><title>I Asked a Java Champion: What Is the Biggest Problem That Professional Java Developers Are Facing Today?</title><link>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/victor_biggest_problem_for_java_devs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/victor_biggest_problem_for_java_devs/</guid><description>
I have attended the workshop that is organized by the ITKonekt. The workshop was about efficient coding practices for best performance in Java. Java Champion Victor Rentea did a great job explaining all java internals, tools, hibernate, threads, collections, garbage collections, and much more. It was very enjoyable to learn from him, and I decided to ask him the question:
What is the biggest problem that professional Java developers are facing today?</description></item><item><title>10 Mistakes That Java Developers Make That Prevent Them From Being Successful Developers</title><link>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/teen_mistakes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/teen_mistakes/</guid><description>
Based on my previous experience, I created a list of 10 mistakes that developers made, preventing them from being a great developer. Here is the list:
1. Not writing unit tests Developers that don’t write unit tests produce more bugs from the code they write and maintain. That leads to unstable products and client dissatisfaction.
If you are not familiar with writing unit tests, there are some resources to get started with:</description></item><item><title>How do I become proficient with functional programming in Java</title><link>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/start_fp_in_java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.professionaldev.pro/post/java/start_fp_in_java/</guid><description>
As a Java developer, I always look for ways to improve my coding skills. I heard about functional programming (FP) back when I was a student. Then, FP was not very popular and most developers considered code written using FP to be slow.
Time has changed and today FP is very popular. Some developers are considering it to be the future of how developers write code.
FP is the most useful concept that I learned in the last several years.</description></item></channel></rss>